DAVE POWELL

Hurst, TX 76053

Phone: (214) 289-7597 | Email: evadllewop@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <u>/dave-powell-842b455/</u> | GitHub: <u>/evadllewop</u> | Behance: <u>/DavePowell</u>

SUMMARY

Passionate web designer/full stack developer leveraging 8 + years of extensive experience in creative design, digital marketing, development, conceptualizing and problem solving who currently seeks a full-time web development position. Development education stems from Southern Methodist University along with years of collaborating with various smart and talented colleagues and teams within the structure of large successful corporations.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML • CSS • JavaScript • ES6 • jQuery • AJAX • Node.js • JSON • MySQL • MongoDB • Mongoose • React • GitHub • Bootstrap • WordPress • Adobe Creative Suite • Sketch • UI Design • UX Design • Digital Design

DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Workout Tracker | Github Repository | Deployed Site

- Summary: Workout tracker created with MongoDB with a Mongoose schema and routes with Express.
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: Semantic HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap, Express, Node, MongoDB, Mongoose

Burger Logger | Github Repository | Deployed Site

- Summary: A burger logger created with MySQL, Node, Express, Handlebars and a homemade ORM (yum!).
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: HTML, CSS, Node.is, Javascript, MySQL, Express, Handlebars

EXPERIENCE

Wordpress Designer/Developer The Old State/Saloon

2020 - 2021

Hurst, TX

Design and development of various projects.

Key Accomplishments:

- Specialized in Wordpress design and development
- Graduated from Southern Methodist University with a certificate for full stack web development.

UX/UI Designer, Consultant

2015 - 2018

Sabre

Southlake, TX

Lead UX/UI designer within a specialized team for the conceptualizing and prototyping of new up-and-coming products.

Key Accomplishments:

- Upgraded brand identity by delivering attractive, user-friendly and consistent patterns across the entire portfolio.
- Advised and mentored team members on design issues and served as a bridge between UX and internal design language team members.
- Conducted usability testing and post-deployment evaluations to measure user experience success.

Visual Designer 2015 - 2015 AIM Consulting

Addison, TX

Led visual design for a specific client who was not responding to previous designs.

Key Accomplishments:

- Successfully delivered new branding and client-facing interface enhancements.
- Enhanced website with responsive solutions
- Headed up all communications with development teams to ensure proper implementation

Web Designer 2014 - 2015

AT&T Foundry

Plano, TX

Delivered optimized and usable interfaces for AT&T services applications.

Key Accomplishments:

- Revamped look and feel for a major path within the AT&T infrastructure
- Rapidly developed and iterated product and feature prototypes from conceptual demonstrations.
- Delivered all screen-flow diagrams and UI spec documentation for developers.

Mobile UI Designer 2012 - 2014

Seven Tablets

Plano, TX

Designed optimized and usable interfaces for native mobile applications.

Key Accomplishments:

• Led visual design for a suite of apps and overall concept and design for promotional mini-site.

Web Designer 2011 - 2012

Match.com

Dallas, TX

Designed user interface, and web pages to meet branding guidelines and web best practices.

Key Accomplishments:

- STIR.com branding/UI design for desktop and mobile web pages, emails and all supporting initiatives.
- Chemistry.com website design
- Chemistry.com Flash mini-game concepts and designs.

Web Designer 2008 - 2011

Travelocity

Dallas, TX

Key member of Travelocity's I.D. (Innovation Design) Team.

Key Accomplishments:

- Led design for Travelocity's "Global Trips" (shopping and checkout path for Travelocity and Travelocity partners worldwide)
- "Innovator of the Year Award" for established companies at the Travel Industry Association's annual TravelCom conference in 2008.
- Contributing Designer, Flash Developer and IA for Travelocity's ExperienceFinder (travel research/ planning tool, destination stores and media vehicle) application.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp, Southern Methodist University - Dallas, TX

Degree or Certification, Full Stack Web Development - Southern Methodist University